October 30th, Stellar Year 2148
It won't move!
Mine, either! I'm getting out!
Hide behind your Juggernaut.
They're still shooting.
Kurena, are you okay?
If you can move, hide behind it!
Damn! They got me!
Is this the end?
Shin!
You sure that's how
you want to handle this?
Yeah. We can't take him with us.
It's the least we can do.
And...
we won't be going much farther ourselves.
Shin's is the only one
that still moves, huh?
We've got rifles and guns, but...
Not a lot of ammo.
We lost the containers, which hurts.
We lost most of our ammo and fuel.
And food!
Yup. Food, too.
I'm all done.
What about you?
All set.
Let's go, then.
If we don't get out of here,
the Legion will find us again.
Yeah.
Who'll pilot?
It can't just be Shin all the time.
We'll take shifts.
That's fine.
But did it have to be Undertaker,
of all things?
Is that a problem?
Shin sets his parameters so tight
that it's scary.
And he's got a lot of limiters turned off.
I'll go first, then.
No, I'll do it.
You were just complaining.
And I lost mine first,
so I'm not tired at all.
Okay, if we run into any Legion,
the one piloting at the time fights them, right?
Fine with me.
Fine!
Kurena, stop.
There's a hole in those cliffs
at 10 o'clock.
Take us there.
Roger.
Hurry.
We avoided them, thanks to Shin.
There were a whole lot of them, though.
Is it just me, or are
we seeing more of them lately?
I guess we're getting closer
to their base.
Yeah.
Everybody, eyes front.
Imperial City First Elementary School
A school?
You think?
Probably.
That's right.
You've never been to school, have you?
Even in a totally different country and culture,
schools still look basically the same.
So this is a school...
Hey, let's sleep here today!
Let's.
Can you read that, Kurena?
Nope.
But it looks like they were having fun.
This brings back so many memories.
Did you like school and studying?
Nope.
Raiden Shuga!
Huh? Is Raiden absent today?
Present!
Okay.
Theoto Rikka.
Here!
Kurena Kukumila.
Present!
Anju Emma!
Present.
Shinei Nouzen!
If we're not going to study,
these are just firewood.
I see.
Is this something special, too?
Tearing down the school, maybe?
Okay. How do we light it?
Those are textbooks!
I feel kind of guilty.
Books we can't read are useless.
True.
Nihonica Workbook
Well done!
You still have one left?
Yeah.
This is the last one.
No more after-dinner desserts!
October 31st, Stellar Year 2148
This is all of it.
We'll be lucky if it lasts the full day.
Yeah.
I guess our fun hike is at an end.
We're leaving!
Okay!
It's my turn this morning, right?
Yeah. Thanks.
We graduated school in a single day, huh?
Wow, we must be really smart!
We've got bright futures ahead of us.
Hey!
We're going up this?
Don't ask me.
Is this right?
We keep going forward, right?
Yes.
Roger.
Anju, let's switch.
It's still early, isn't it?
It was supposed to be
my shift until lunch.
I'm bored.
You scared me!
How silly!
Yeah, I didn't think
we'd have so much free time.
There's nothing to do
but look at the scenery.
Shin should've brought a picture book
from that school.
Yeah.
Get some rest.
I'm not tired at all.
We're all set here, Shin.
You're on watch, Kurena.
Take my place!
The one piloting fights.
That's the rule, right?
You knew from the start!
There's a unit we won't be able to dodge.
And if we can't dodge them,
we'll have to fight.
So you suggested switching...
That's not fair, Shin!
You can't do this to us!
You keep going.
They won't find you
in the forest for a while.
Keep going, and you'll get to a point
where the Legion's voices disappear.
If anybody's alive, ask them for help.
Hell, no!
That means you're going
to be a decoy, right?
We're all going together, right?
You can't leave us at the very end...
and go by yourself!
That's not fair!
Damn! He turned it off!
That idiot!
Wait!
I'm going, too.
You're okay with this, right?
We can't let Shin go by himself, right?
Right.
That ultra-long-range cannon from before...
I'll kill you.
The men, the women, the children,
the old, the nobles, the peasants...
I'll kill everyone...
everyone who threatens the princess!
Not now...
They're after my head, huh?
Shin!
Shit! Look at me, damn it!
I'm coming!
Don't give up!
Get moving!
Shin! Shin!
Can you hear me?
Shin, answer me!
You're all fools.
You can't beat the Legion
with those weapons.
I'm out of ammo!
Theo!
Damn it!
Fools...
You really are... fools.
When I'm part of the Legion,
whose name will I call out?
October 13th,  Stellar Year 2148
Fido's not here.
They took him.
So he wasn't a dog, huh?
Major Milizé, was it?
Yes.
What are you doing
all the way out here?
You're under house arrest, aren't you?
Yes.
Which gives me time
to visit the front lines.
Along with the next group to be executed?
I heard the rumors,
but you're really a weirdo, huh?
Go see it.
Not that they left much behind.
Okay.
I've been watching the kids go off
on their last march for a long time.
But I've never seen a Handler come out here.
Lieutenant Aldrecht, you're...
An Alba. Just like you.
My wife was an Eighty-Six.
When they were coming
to take my wife and daughter,
I dyed my hair and went with them.
I volunteered,
hoping to get their rights back.
But they both died on the battlefield.
After Shin came,
when nobody was listening, I asked him
if there were any Legion
out there looking for
a shithead who couldn't protect
his wife and daughter.
And what would've you have done
if there were?
Go out there and let them kill me.
But he said there weren't.
He said there weren't any Legion
calling my name.
It made me feel a little better.
My wife and daughter weren't stuck
on the battlefield even after death.
Once I'm on the other side,
I'll see them.
I always tell them I'm an Alba
before they go on their special recon mission.
I tell them that they're free to hate us.
They can even kill me
if it'll make them feel better.
But nobody ever does.
Not this time, either.
So I'm still here.
I've kept you too long.
Get going.
Thank you.
We keep it at the barracks.
It's a black cat with white paws.
And for some reason, it's taken more of a liking
to Undertaker than anyone.
He doesn't play with it at all.
It rubs up against him all the time,
and he just pats it once in a while.
I think it's more like
it thinks he's a good bed.
I mean... Just look at it right now.
Yeah, it doesn't move when he's reading.
It'll never get along with
Black Dog, though. He's annoying.
That's mean! And not fair!
I demand you take that back!
Boo! Boo!
What's its name?
Blackie.
Whitey.
Two-Tone.
Kitty.
Shrimp.
Remarque.
Don't name it after the author of
whatever book you're reading now.
And what are you even reading?
You have such bad taste.
If you actually went to the
trouble of finding this,
you're one crazy dumbass.
Raiden Shuga.
I'll put everyone's names down.
I bet you'd cry because you didn't know
who was who, otherwise.
Theoto Rikka.
Take care of the cat.
You might as well, if you're
gonna insist on being a saint.
Kurena Kukumila.
We still haven't decided on a name yet.
Give it a cute one, okay, Major?
Anju Emma.
If, one day, you make it
to our final destination,
would you please leave flowers?
Shinei Nouzen.
I can keep walking, too.
They believed that about me,
until the very end.
Let's go.
What should I call you?
I'll fight...
until the moment
when fate finally comes for me.
Shin...
I'm sorry.
I kept calling you,
and I made you come all the way here.
Let's go.
"The Poppies Bloom Red on the Battlefield"